欢迎来到第一次实际讲座
Welcome to the first actual lecture
本课程的。
of this course.
现在这个课程很有可能
Now there is a good chance that this course
将是你的第一次接触
is going to be your very first contact
与任何网络开发。
with any web development.
所以在我们开始编写 HTML 和 CSS 代码之前，
And so before we start writing HTML and CSS code,
我认为这可能是个好主意
I think it might be a good idea
真正开始这门课程
to actually begin this course
具有非常高水平的概述
with a very high level overview
Web 开发的这个领域。
of this field of web development.
所以我们将讨论诸如
So we're going to talk about things like
客户端和服务器，前端和后端开发，
clients and servers, front-end and back-end development,
静态和动态网站。
static and dynamic websites.
当然还有核心语言
And of course about the core languages
和Web开发的核心技术。
and core technologies of web development.
我要解释这一切
And I'm going to explain all this
围绕发生的过程
around the process that happens
当我们在浏览器中打开网页时。
when we open up a webpage in a browser.
再一次记住，
Just keep in mind again,
这只是一个高级概述。
that this is just a high-level overview.
所以我会在这里省略很多细节。
And so I'm going to leave out a lot of details here.
这真的只是让你熟悉
This is really just so you get familiar
使用其中一些概念和术语
with some of these concepts and terms
所有 Web 开发人员都知道
that all web developers know
在您开始自己的旅程之前。
before you start your own journey.
但无论如何，假设我们正在尝试访问一个网页
But anyway, let's say that we're trying to access a webpage
在我们的浏览器中omnifood.dev
in our browser at omnifood.dev
顺便说一句，这实际上是网站
And by the way, this is actually the website
我们将在整个课程中发展。
that we're going to develop throughout this course.
现在，当我们尝试访问此页面时会发生什么
Now what happens as we try to access this page
就是我们的浏览器会向服务器发送请求
is that our browser will send a request to the server
此页面托管在 Internet 上的位置。
where this page is hosted on the internet.
所以每个网站都被存储
So each and every website is stored
在称为服务器的东西上，它基本上是一台计算机
on something called a Server, which is basically a computer
连接到互联网的
that is connected to the internet
并且能够接收这样的请求。
and is able to receive requests like this one.
同样，当我们浏览某个网站时，
So again, when we browse to a certain website,
我们的网络浏览器将向服务器发送请求
our web browser will send a request to the server
网站的存储位置。
所以它托管在哪里。
where the website is stored.
So where it is hosted.
那么当服务器收到请求时，
Then when the server receives the request,
它将获取构成网站的所有文件
it will take all the files that make up the website
并将它们发送回浏览器。
and send them back to the browser.
所以我们说服务器向浏览器发送响应，
And so we say that the server sends response to the browser,
它基本上包含所有这些文件
which essentially contains all of these files
该网站是由。
that the website is made of.
现在，从这些文件扩展名中可以看出，
Now, as you can see from these file extensions,
我们这里有一些 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript 代码。
we have some HTML, CSS, and also a JavaScript code here.
而这正是这三种语言
And these are precisely the three languages
浏览器可以理解的。
that browsers can understand.
所以这意味着所有的代码
So what this means is that all of the code
组成一个网站的东西总是需要写的
that makes up a website needs to always be written
在 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript 中。
in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
因为再一次，这些本质上是
Because again, these are essentially
任何浏览器都能理解的三大核心技术。
the three core technologies that any browser can understand.
好的，现在，一旦浏览器收到
All right, now, once the browser receives
这些 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript 文件
these HTML, CSS, and JavaScript files
从服务响应中，
from the service response,
它将获取代码并呈现网站
it will take the code and render the website
我们试图访问。
that we were trying to access.
所以基于那个代码，好吧。
So based on that code, okay.
有了这个，你已经有了很好的理解
And with this, you already have a good understanding
当我们浏览一个网站时实际发生了什么
of what actually happens when we browse to a website
还有关于技术
and also about the technologies
我们用来建立任何网站
that we use to build any website
以及编写 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript 代码的过程
and that process of writing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code
浏览器可以理解的
that the browser can understand
是一个过程我们称之为前端 Web 开发。
is the process that we call Front-End Web Development.
所以每当你听到某人
So whenever you hear someone
谈论前端开发，
talking about Front-End Development,
他们的意思是开发人员编写代码
what they mean is developers writing the code
显示在浏览器中，
that is displayed in a browser,
这基本上是网站的前端。
which is basically the front-end of a website.
事实上，这基本上就是我们要学习的内容
And in fact, this is essentially what we're going to learn
在这门课程中，或者至少是非常非常基础的课程
in this course, or at least the very, very fundamentals
前端开发，
of front-end development,
这是学习HTML和CSS。
which is learning HTML and CSS.
现在，就像这里的旁注一样，
Now, just as a side note here,
每当组成网站的文件
whenever the files that make up the website
只是存储在网络服务器上
are simply stored on a web server
然后按原样发送到浏览器，
and are then sent to the browser as they are,
我们说我们有一个静态网站。
we say that we have a static website.
好的。
Okay.
这将在一分钟内变得更有意义
And this will make a little bit more sense in a minute
当我们谈论什么是动态网站时，
when we talk about what a dynamic website is,
但现在，请记住，静态网站
but for now, just keep in mind that a static website
基本上是一个网站，其中的文件
is basically a website where the files
只是简单地从服务器发送到浏览器。
are simply sent from the server to the browser as they are.
所以没有任何转变。
So without any transformation.
好的。
All right.
所以我希望由此，
So I hope that from this,
你了解了什么是前端开发
you learned what front-end development is
还有关于三大核心技术
and also about the three core technologies
构成任何网站。
that make up any website.
所以现在，让我们更进一步
And so now, let's take it one step further
并谈论一个叫做后端开发的东西。
and talk about something called Back-end Development.
所以让我们在这里尝试另一个例子。
So let's try another example here.
而这一次，让我们试着去理解
And this time, let's try to understand
会发生什么
what would happen
当我们尝试访问像 udemy.com 这样的网站时
when we try to access a website like udemy.com
所以再一次，第一步是一个请求
So once again, the first step is that a request
发送到托管 udemy.com 的 Web 服务器。
is sent to the web server where udemy.com is hosted.
现在，为什么像 Udemy 这样的网站，
Now, why is a website like Udemy,
与静态 Omnifood 网站之类的网站如此不同
so different from something like the static Omnifood website
我之前给你看的？
that I showed you earlier?
好吧，像您这样的复杂网站 udemy.com
Well, a complex site like you udemy.com
真的和静态网站完全不同，
is really completely different from a static site,
因为内容很多
because there is a lot of content
这一直在变化。
that is always changing all the time.
就像在 Udemy 上一样，总是有新课程
Like on Udemy, there are always new courses
和新的评论被添加到网站。
and new reviews being added to the site.
新评级和新课程长度
New ratings and new course length
例如计算，
are calculated for example,
还有很多类似的东西
and really a bunch of other things like that
总是在发生。
are always happening.
所以为了让这样的系统工作，
And so in order to make a system like this work,
udemy.com 需要一个完整的应用程序
udemy.com needs a whole application
在服务器上运行，他们还需要一个大数据库，
running on the server, and they also need a big database,
基本上包含了所有的课程
which basically contains all the courses
以及所有的评论，所有的用户，
and all the reviews, all the users,
真的是所有的内容
and really all the content
正在他们的网站上显示。
that is being displayed on their website.
现在要做这一切，前端技术
Now to do all this, front-end technologies
像 HTML 和 CSS 是不够的。
like HTML and CSS are simply not enough.
所以基本上你将在这门课程中学到的东西，
So basically with what you're going to learn in this course,
你不能
you're not going to be able
构建类似 udemy.com 的东西
to build something like udemy.com
好的。
All right.
所以要写应用程序
So to write applications
实际在 Web 服务器上执行，
that are actually executed on web servers,
开发人员使用某种后端语言
developers use some kind of back-end language
比如 Node JS、PHP 或 Python。
like Node JS, PHP, or Python.
所以这些语言所做的就是从数据库中取出数据
So what these languages do is to take data out of a database
并且基本上将这些数据组装到最终文件中
and basically assemble that data into the final files
然后将其作为响应发送到浏览器。135
that will then be sent to the browser as the response.
而这整个过程被称为后端开发，
And this whole process is called Back-end Development,
因为这基本上是网站的不可见部分。
because this is basically the invisible part of a website.
所以它是网站的后端。
And so it's the website's back-end.
现在在这种情况下，我们说我们有一个动态网站
Now in this situation, we say that we have a dynamic website
因为网站是动态组装的
because the website is dynamically assembled
来自服务器上的不同部分。
from different pieces on the server.
每次有人访问该网站时都会发生这种情况。
And that happens each time that someone visits the website.
所以回到udemy.com的例子
So returning to the example of udemy.com
事实上，每次你访问 Udemy，
In fact, each time that you visit Udemy,
将生成一个新版本的网站
a new version of the website is going to be generated
从他们的数据库中并发送到您的浏览器。
from their database and sent to your browser.
现在，另一方面，如果 udemy 是一个静态网站，
Now, on the other hand, if udemy was a static website,
然后是网站文件
then the website files
已经坐在服务器上，
would already be sitting on the server,
只是在等待有人访问它们。
just waiting for someone to access them.
好的？
Okay?
这就是静态和动态之间的最大区别
So that's the big difference between static and dynamic
在静态中，文件已经完成
In static, the files are already done
在动态中，它们首先需要生成
and in dynamic, they first need to be generated
通过在服务器上运行的应用程序。
by an application that is running on the server.
好的。
All right.
但是现在剩下的过程
But now the rest of the process
实际上和以前一样。
is actually the same as before.
所以这些文件现在可以发送到浏览器了
So these files are now ready to be sent to the browser
作为响应，然后将其转换
as a response, which will then be converted
到最终网站
to the final website
就像我们在这里看到的 udemy.com 一样。
like this one we see here of udemy.com.
伟大的。现在当然，
Great. Now of course,
你不需要记住所有这些名字
there is no need for you to memorize all these names
我在这里提到的，
that I mentioned here,
也不需要深入了解这个过程。
and also no need to deeply understand this process.
我只想给你一个概述
All I want here is to give you an overview
前端和后端实际上是什么，
of what front-end and back-end actually are,
浏览器和服务器是什么。
what the browser and the server are.
还有什么是静态和动态网站，
And also what static and dynamic websites are,
因为我真的认为这将是
because I really think that this is going to be
在您开始开发者之旅时非常有帮助。
extremely helpful as you start your developer journey.
但现在，为了结束，让我们仔细看看
But now, just to finish, let's take a closer look
在前端的三种语言。
at the three languages of the front-end.
所以 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript。
So HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
从 HTML 开始，
And starting with HTML,
HTML 负责页面的内容。
HTML is responsible for the content of the page.
这就是文本、图像、按钮，
So that's the text, the images, the buttons,
以及您在网页上看到的所有内容
and really all the content that you see on a webpage
总是写在 HTML 文件中。
is always written inside an HTML file.
然后CSS负责
Then the CSS is responsible
用于呈现该内容。
for the presentation of that content.
所以基本上是为了造型
So basically for styling
以及在网页上布置元素。
and for laying out the elements on the webpage.
现在终于，JavaScript 是真正的编程语言
Now finally, JavaScript is the actual programming language
的前端。
of the front-end.
所以它允许我们添加动态
So it allows us to add dynamic
和网页的交互效果。
and interactive effects to webpages.
我们还可以使用它来操作内容或 CSS
We can also use it to manipulate the content or the CSS
从 Web 服务器加载数据
to load data from web servers
甚至构建整个前端应用程序，
and even to build entire front-end applications,
然后我们称之为网络应用程序。
which we then call web applications.
现在我们也可以使用类比
Now we can also use the analogy
名词、目标和动词
of nouns, objectives, and verbs
在这里进行角色分离
to make the separation of roles here
更容易理解。
a little bit easier to understand.
所以在这个类比中，
HTML 代表名词。
So in this analogy,
HTML represents the nouns.
例如，说
P元素是一个段落。
For example, saying that
the P element is a paragraph.
所以段落是这里的名词。
So paragraph is the noun here.
CSS然后是目标
The CSS then is the objective
因为它基本上描述了名词。
because it basically describes the noun.
比如像这一段 CSS
For example, like this piece of CSS
说段落文本是红色的。
saying that the paragraph text is red.
所以红色是描述名词的目标。
And so red is the objective describing the noun.
好的。
All right.
最后，JavaScript 当然是动词，
Finally, JavaScript is of course the verb,
就像说隐藏段落。
like saying hide the paragraph.
所以我们实际上在这里做一些事情。
So we're actually doing something here.
所以我们有一个动词。
And so we have a verb.
好的。 那有意义吗？
Okay. Does that make sense?
好的。 有了这个，
All right. And with this,
我们完成了对 Web 开发的介绍。
we finish our introduction to web development.
所以我们现在已经准备好开始工作了
And so we're now ready to start working
在他的课程中使用 HTML 和 CSS 代码。
with HTML and CSS code in his course.